<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The home of ShedCode]]></title>
  <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-18T22:08:54+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://shedcode.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Jefferies]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ShedCode]]></title>
    <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/2012/08/01/shedcode/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T14:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://shedcode.github.com/2012/08/01/shedcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://shedcode.github.com/images/jamesjefferies-photo.jpg" width="200" height="200" title="James Jefferies" > Hi, I&#8217;m <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">James Jefferies</a>, a Software Engineer &amp; Technologist. I formed ShedCode in the Summer of 2011 to work on interesting projects with interesting people.</p>

<p>After many years of being an employee for large companies, solving problems by thinking hard &amp; asking computers to help, I wanted to be more flexible with who I could work with &amp; what I worked on.</p>

<p>I love to fix all kinds of problems, from building bespoke web, desktop &amp; mobile applications, performance consultancy, architecture and general technical advice.</p>

<p>Sometimes I work on my own, or with a client&#8217;s team. Other times, I am able to team up with some of the experts I&#8217;ve worked with over the years. From User Experience designers, to System Technicians, to Project Managers and Testers to provide a full solution.</p>

<h2>Current Project Highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://jamesjefferies.com/2012/11/11/steam-powered-arduino-part-1/">Steam powered Arduino</a></li>
<li>Finance Portal - web application enabling statements and payements for a client</li>
<li>Roster - speed dating for railway engines</li>
</ul>


<h2>Past Project Highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://happenstanceproject.com">Happenstance</a> Project (Digital R&amp;D fund)</li>
<li>Application forms for the <a href="http://www.theco-operativebank.co.uk">Co-operative Bank</a> with <a href="http://www.technophobia.com">Technophobia</a></li>
<li>Recruitment system for South Yorkshire Police</li>
<li>Platform for Technology Strategy Board, <a href="http://ktn.innovateuk.org">_connect</a></li>
<li>Meter reading systems &amp; Mobile meter installation systems for what is now <a href="http://www.rwe.com/web/cms/en/97770/rwe-npower/about-us/">RWE npowerRWE</a></li>
<li>Customer Relationship Management application &amp; infrastructure architecture for <a href="http://www.barclays.co.uk">Barclays Bank</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tech</h2>

<p>Many years of Java experience, including Grails. Recently started learning Rails and iOS for some startup project prototypes.</p>

<p>At home in Linux land, but also have been a Mac user for the last 10 years.</p>

<p>Also currently investigating Arduinos for electronic projects.</p>

<h2>Github</h2>

<p>I have recently started to use GitHub for code I think other people will find useful (as well as this site and <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">jamesjefferies.com</a>) - you can see the ruby script I wrote for receiving the <a href="https://github.com/jamesjefferies/national-rail-datafeeds-ruby-examples">Network Rail Data Feeds</a> as a way of learning about them and Ruby. There are also many blog posts about what I learnt on my <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">blog</a></p>

<h2>Where are we?</h2>

<p>ShedCode is based in an office above the <a href="http://sitegallery.org">Site Gallery</a> in Sheffield, South Yorkshire. Pop in to see us for a chat in the cafe downstairs!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
