<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The home of ShedCode]]></title>
  <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-07T11:26:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://shedcode.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Jefferies]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ShedCode]]></title>
    <link href="http://shedcode.github.com/2012/08/01/shedcode/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T14:20:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://shedcode.github.com/2012/08/01/shedcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://shedcode.github.com/images/jamesjefferies-photo.jpg" width="200" height="200" title="James Jefferies" > Hi, I&#8217;m <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">James Jefferies</a>, a Software Engineer &amp; Technologist. I formed ShedCode in the Summer of 2011 to work on interesting projects with interesting people.</p>

<p>After many years of being an employee for large companies, solving problems by thinking hard &amp; asking computers to help, I wanted to be more flexible with who I could work with &amp; what I worked on.</p>

<p>I love to fix all kinds of problems, from building bespoke web, desktop &amp; mobile applications, performance consultancy, server administration, technical architecture and general technical advice.</p>

<h2>Contact ShedCode</h2>

<p>ShedCode is based in an office above the <a href="http://sitegallery.org">Site Gallery</a> in Sheffield, South Yorkshire. Pop in to see us for a chat in the cafe downstairs!</p>

<p>You can email us at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#x3a;&#104;&#101;&#108;&#x6c;&#111;&#64;&#x73;&#104;&#x65;&#100;&#x63;&#x6f;&#100;&#x65;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#46;&#117;&#x6b;">&#104;&#x65;&#108;&#108;&#111;&#x40;&#x73;&#104;&#101;&#x64;&#x63;&#x6f;&#x64;&#x65;&#46;&#x63;&#111;&#x2e;&#117;&#x6b;</a> or our twitter accounts are <a href="http://twitter.com/shedcode">@shedcode</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/jamesjefferies">@jamesjefferies</a>. Here is my <a href="uk.linkedin.com/in/jamesjefferies/">LinkedIn profile</a>.</p>

<h2>Project Highlights</h2>

<ul>
<li><p>Finance Portal - Web application enabling statements and payments for a financial services client with <a href="http://www.technophobia.com">Technophobia</a> - built using lightweight Java stack.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://happenstanceproject.com">Happenstance</a> Project (Digital R&amp;D fund)</p></li>
<li><p>Application forms for the <a href="http://www.theco-operativebank.co.uk">Co-operative Bank</a> with <a href="http://www.technophobia.com">Technophobia</a> - built using the JSF, Spring, Hibernate, Java stack.</p></li>
<li><p>Password storage, retrieval system - internal system built using Grails &amp; Groovy.</p></li>
<li><p>Recruitment system for South Yorkshire Police with <a href="http://www.technophobia.com">Technophobia</a> - built using the JSF, Spring, Hibernate, Java stack.</p></li>
<li><p>Meter reading systems &amp; Mobile meter installation systems for what is now <a href="http://www.rwe.com/web/cms/en/97770/rwe-npower/about-us/">RWE npowerRWE</a></p></li>
<li><p>Barclays Bank - my first proper job, Customer Relationship Management application &amp; infrastructure architecture for <a href="http://www.barclays.co.uk">Barclays Bank</a></p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Tech</h2>

<h3>Java</h3>

<p>Way back in 1999 I was sent on a &#8216;Java for C Programmers&#8217; course which opened my eyes to the power (and some of the pain!) of the Java language. Since then I&#8217;ve spent most of my time building applications to run in the Java ecosystem. It&#8217;s my fallback language now &amp; I have a lot of experience working with many of the common Java libraries &amp; frameworks, Spring, JSF, Struts, iText, Junit,  Hibernate.</p>

<h3>Grails and Groovy</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve worked on a few Grails projects and have enjoyed how productive the framework is, whilst still being built on many familiar Java frameworks. My platform of choice for JVM applications.</p>

<h3>Rails and Ruby</h3>

<p>Recently I&#8217;ve started learning Ruby, Rails &amp; Sinatra - it&#8217;s obvious to see why Rails &amp; Sinatra are so popular for rapid building of prototypes, proofs of concept and startup MVPs.</p>

<h3>HTML/CSS/JavaScript</h3>

<p>Most applications I have worked on over the last 10 years have been web applications, so I&#8217;m very familiar with HTML and have probably spent most of my JavaScript development time using jQuery &amp; Prototype on those applications.</p>

<p>It is fair to say that my CSS knowledge is somewhat rudimentary. I can get by, but I&#8217;ve had the fortune to work with some excellent front end developers over the years and usually call on them for assistance if required.</p>

<h3>Linux/Unix</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m most at home at a unix like command prompt. Preferably with zsh &amp; screen installed, ready to go. Having learnt unix shell, way back at University, I&#8217;ve a lot of experience of working in that world.</p>

<p>Over all that time, I&#8217;ve picked up a lot of systems admin knowledge and skills, although I wouldn&#8217;t claim to be an admin, I can get a server up and running, secured and raring to go without too much problem.</p>

<p>Having used AIX &amp; Solaris for a lot my career, in recent years I&#8217;ve spent a lot more time with Debian &amp; Ubuntu and they are my operating systems of choice for server builds.</p>

<p>I do admin for a couple of clients, looking after 3 servers at the moment, providing them with technical &amp; hosting support, including domains and DNS.</p>

<h3>Mac OS X and iOS</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m not an old school Apple fan, but in 2003 I bought my first Mac, a secondhand PowerBook, and since then, have weaned friends and family off Windows XP to join the world of OS X. It&#8217;s not perfect, but it works for me, has a Unix variant behind the scenes &amp; is reliable.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve recently beein doing some work getting to know iOS, Objective-C &amp; Cocoa development.</p>

<h3>Database Technologies</h3>

<p>Recently I&#8217;ve been working a lot with MySQL and Postgres, however before that I spent many years working with Oracle Databases (8i, 9i, 10g) and their Java Application Stack.</p>

<h3>Electronics, Arduinos, RaspberryPis</h3>

<p>Many years ago, I had a 100 in 1 electronics kit, recently my interest in electronics has resurfaced, thanks to having an Arduino to work with. I&#8217;ve recently been working with attempting to run an Arduino and printer with <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com/2012/11/11/steam-powered-arduino-part-1/">steam power</a>.</p>

<h2>How do I work?</h2>

<p>Over the years I&#8217;ve worked on many types of project, from classic waterfall projects through to those using various Agile methodologies. I think it is fair to say that most projects have either been very waterfall like, or have incorporated some of the classic Agile methodologies.</p>

<p>Although I know and understand how waterfall projects work, I&#8217;d much prefer to work in a more Agile way, especially with daily standup meeting/scrums for integrated teams, product owners managing priorities, test driven development, continous integration, process automation etc.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also worked on projects where I&#8217;ve taken a brief or existing product away to work on with regular milestone checks, I&#8217;m able to think on my feet and use my experience to work without supervision.</p>

<h2>How do I write code?</h2>

<ul>
<li>I&#8217;m a fan of test driven development, in a pragmatic fashion. Not all my code has test coverage, but most of it usually has. Critical functionality <em>always</em> has coverage!</li>
<li>Although I have done some work in a pair programming environment, it has been unusual in my career to do that. When I have done it, it has usually been for a certain period to crack a specific piece of functionality or problem, rather than continously. It&#8217;s great to learn from other people!</li>
<li>I like processes to be automated where possible. For example, a computer can run my tests for me and let me know if I&#8217;ve made a mistake, whilst I&#8217;m working on other things.</li>
<li>I use IDEs (Eclipse, SpringSource Tool Suite, IntelliJ IDEA) but also do a lot of work in good old vi.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Github</h2>

<p>I have recently started to use GitHub for code I think other people will find useful (as well as this site and <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">jamesjefferies.com</a>) - you can see the ruby script I wrote for receiving the <a href="https://github.com/jamesjefferies/national-rail-datafeeds-ruby-examples">Network Rail Data Feeds</a> as a way of learning about them and Ruby. There are also many blog posts about what I learnt on my <a href="http://jamesjefferies.com">blog</a></p>

<h2>Finally</h2>

<p>Thanks for taking the time to have a look at ShedCode!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
